Guide to the Mark Weinbaum Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1916-72; Series I; 4; (10 boxes)
  - INCOMING
    - Karsavin, Pavel, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Katenev, Nikolai, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Kerensky, Aleksandr, 1938-56 (Box 4, Folder 147-48)
    - KHodasevich, Vladislav, 1939 Mar 8 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - KHomiakov, Gennadii, 1948-49 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - KHrabrov, N., 1932-40, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 151-53)
    - Klenovskii, Dmitrii, 1953-66 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Klimov, E., 1961-71 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Kolyshko, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Komiakov, N.
      See: Russkoe ob"edinënnoe.. ., Box 6, folder 293
    - Komitet po delam bezhentsev pravoslavnogo veroispovedaniia, 1948-49 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Korovnikov, Sergei, 1949-71 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Koshits, Nina, 1949-65, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Krachkovskii, D.
      See: Dmitrii Klenovskii, Box 4, folder 154
    - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1942-50 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Krotkov IUrii, 1969-71 (Box 4, Folder 161-62)
    - Kruzenshtern-Peterets, IUstin'ia, 1969-70 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Krymov, VLadimir, 1938-67, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Krymova, Berta, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Kuskova, Ekaterina, 1946-59 (Box 4, Folder 166-98)
    - Kuznetsov, Anatolii, 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Kuznetsov, S., 1957-70, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 200-01)
      See also: Tarnerov (Third party), Box 10, folder 489
    - Kuznetsova, Galina, 1950-69 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - "L" general, 1937-72 (Box 5, Folder 203-04)
    - Ladinskii, Antonii, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Landau, M.
      See: Mark Aldanov, Box 1, folder 8
    - Lebedev, Vladimir, 1937-44, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 206-12)
      See also: L'Oeuvre (Third party), Box 9, folder 434
    - Lekhovich, V., 1929, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Leontii, Bishop of Chicago, 1936-57 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - Levin, Iosif, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - Levin, Veniamin, 1938, n.d.
    - Levitskii, Sergei, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Lifar, Serge, 1938-40 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - Lisitsyn, IA, 1939-43 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Litvinskii, V.
      See: Vladimir Petrov, Box 6, folder 262
    - Lokhvitskaia, Nadezhda
      See: Teffi, Box 7, folder 330
    - Losskii, Nikolai, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Lukash, Ivan, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Lukash, Tamara, 1970-71
    - Lur'e, Artur, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Lur'e, V.
      See: Aleksei Pozniakov, Box 6, folder 275
    - "M" general, 1927-72 (Box 5, Folder 222-24)
    - Maevskii, Vladislav, 1946-64 (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - Makovskii, Sergei, 1961-62 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Maksimov, Sergei, 1948-59, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - Marchenko, N.
      See: Nikolai Narokov, Box 5, folder 239
    - Margolin, IUlii, 1956-70 (Box 5, Folder 228-29)
    - Masainov, Aleksei, 1926-39 (Box 5, Folder 230-32)
    - Meyerhold, Vsevolod, 1927 Apr 11 (Box 5, Folder 233)
    - Mel'gunov, Sergei Mel'gunova, P., 1946-67 (Box 5, Folder 234)
    - Mikhailov, Mikhailo, 1965-70 (Box 5, Folder 235)
    - Muratov, Pavel, 1926-27 (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - "N" general, 1941-70 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir Nabokova, Vera, 1949-72 (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - Narokov, Nikolai, 1957-69 (Box 5, Folder 239-40)
    - Nekrasov, V., 1945-48 (Box 5, Folder 241)
    - Novikov, M., 1957-58 (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - "O" general, 1946-70 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Ob"edinenie poslevoennykh bezhentsev iz SSSR v Zapadnoi Germanii, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina, 1963-72 (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - Osipov, N., 1960-61, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - Ostromyslenskii, Ivan, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - "P" general, 1933-72 (Box 6, Folder 248-51)
    - Pachmuss, Temira, 1969-70 (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - Panteleimonov, Boris, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    - Pantiukhov, Oleg, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - Pashin, S.
      See: Sergei Maksimov, Box 5, folder 227
    - Pastak, S., 1968-70 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - Pavlovskii, P.
      See: Ob"edinenie poslevoennykh ..., Box 5, folder 244
    - La pensée russe
      See: Russkaia mysl', Box 6, folder 292
    - Perov, Pavel, 1959-70 (Box 6, Folder 256-57)
    - Petrishchev, A., 1933-48, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 258-60)
    - Petrov, Victor, 1969-70 (Box 6, Folder 261)
    - Petrov, Vladimir, 1947-69, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 262-66)
    - Pirozhkova, V., 1958-71 (Box 6, Folder 267)
    - Pletnev, Rostislav, 1962-70 (Box 6, Folder 268)
    - Poliakov, Aleksandr, 1970-71 (Box 6, Folder 269)
    - Poltoratskii, Nikolai, 1969-70 (Box 6, Folder 270)
    - Pomerantsev, Kiril, 1961-69 (Box 6, Folder 271)
    - Posev, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 272)
    - Potresov, S.
      See: Sergei IAblonovskii, Box 3, folder 125
    - Pozdniakov, Vladimir, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 273)
    - Pozhidaev, Vsevolod, 1946-70 (Box 6, Folder 274)
    - Pozniakov, Aleksei (encl.), 1932-38 (Box 6, Folder 275)
    - Prokopovich, E.
      See: Ekaterina Kuskova, Box 4, folder 166
    - Pronin, Dmitrii, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    - Pul'man, Fëdor, 1963-65 (Box 6, Folder 277)
    - Pushkarëv, Sergei, 1958-70 (Box 6, Folder 278-80)
    - "R" general, 1924-72 (Box 6, Folder 281-82)
    - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1932, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    - Rafal'skii, Sergei, 1961-71 (Box 6, Folder 284)
    - Reizenberg, Nadezhda, 1941, 1956, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 285)
    - Remizov, Aleksei, 1950-57, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 286-87)
    - R.O.O.V.A.
      See: Russkoe ob"edinennoe obshchestvo.. ., Box 6, folder 293
    - Roshchina-Insarova, Ekaterina, 1954-70 (Box 6, Folder 288)
    - Rubakin, N., 1924-25 (Box 6, Folder 289)
    - Rumanov, Arkadii, 1959-60 (Box 6, Folder 290)
    - Russian War Relief, 1942-45 (Box 6, Folder 291)
    - Russian Consolidated Mutual Aid Society
    - Russkaia mysl', 1955-69 (Box 6, Folder 292)
    - Russkoe ob"edinennoe obshchestvo vzaimopomoshehi v Amerike, 1933, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 293)
    - "S" general, 1916-71 (Box 7, Folder 294-99)
    - Sabaneev, Leonid, 1958-65 (Box 7, Folder 300)
    - Samarin, Vladimir, 1960-71 (Box 7, Folder 301-04)
    - Samusina, Nina, 1951-60 (Box 7, Folder 305)
    - Sedykh, Andrei, 1933-60, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 306)
    - Semeniuk, L., 1961-68, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 307)
    - SHakhovskaia, Zinaida
    - SHakhovskoi, Dmitrii
      See: Ioann, archbishop of San Fransisco, Box 3, folder 131
    - SHiriaev, Boris, 1958-59 (Box 7, Folder 308)
    - SHpolianskii, Arnold
      See: Don-Aminado, Box 2, folder 79
    - Shvarts, Solomon, 1966, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 309)
    - Shvarts-Omonskii, N.
      See: NIkolai Ul'ianov, Box 8, folder 345
    - Sirin, V.
      See: Vladimir Nabokov, Box 5, folder 238
    - Skrylov, Aleksei, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 310)
    - Slonim, Mark, 1964-71, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 311-12)
    - Smirnova-Maksheeva, T., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 313)
    - Smolenskii, Vladimir, 1954, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 314)
    - Soiuz zashchity Kazakov v Germanii, 1971, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 315)
    - Sokolov-Samarin, V.
      See: Vladimir Samarin, Box 7, folder 301
    - Solov'ëv, Mikhail, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 316)
    - Sorin, Savelii, 1939-47 (Box 7, Folder 317)
    - Stepanov, N., 1948-49 (Box 7, Folder 318)
    - Stepanova, Natal'ia, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 319)
    - Stepun, Fëdor, 1957, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 320)
    - Stoianovskaia, Lidiia, 1948, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 321)
    - Stolkind, A., 1959, 1961, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 322)
    - Strannik
      See: Ioann, Archbishop of San Fransisco, Box 3, folder 131
    - Struve, Gleb, 1947-71 (Box 7, Folder 323-24)
    - "T" general, 1932-70 (Box 7, Folder 325-26)
    - Taar, Waldemar
      See: Vladimir Tatarinov, Box 7, folder 329
    - Tamirova, Tamara, 1945, 1953, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 327)
    - Tarydina, Tat'iana, 1964-70 (Box 7, Folder 328)
    - Tatarinov, Vladimir, 194-41, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 329)
    - Teffi, Nadezhda, 1952, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 330-31)
    - Terapiano, IUrii, 1945-53 (Box 7, Folder 332)
    - Timashev, Nikolai, 1960-67 (Box 7, Folder 333-34)
    - Timasheva, Tat'iana, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 335-36)
    - Todorov, Konstantin, 1941-43 (Box 7, Folder 337)
    - Tolstoy, Aleksandra, 1933-70, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 338-39)
    - Tolstovskii fond
      See: Tolstoy Foundation, Box 7, folder 340
    - Tolstoy Foundation, 1942-46 (Box 7, Folder 340)
    - Trubetskoi, IUrii, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 341)
    - Trufanov, Sergei
      See: Iliodor, Box 3, folder 129
    - TSetlin, Mikhail, 1941-42 (Box 7, Folder 342)
    - TSvetinovich, Vasilii
      See: Gruppa russkikh..., Box 3, folder 119
    - Tyrkova-Williams, Ariadna, 1936-57 (Box 7, Folder 343)
    - "U" general, 1962-70 (Box 8, Folder 344)
    - Ul'ianov, Nikolai, 1955-70, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 345)
    - Ul'rich, Elizaveta von, 1969-70 (Box 8, Folder 346)
    - Uranov, Petr, 1951-71 (Box 8, Folder 347)
    - "V" general, 1940-71 (Box 8, Folder 348)
    - Vakar, Nikolai Vakar, G., 1941-69 (Box 8, Folder 349)
    - Valentinov, N.
    - Veidle, Vladimir, 1957-72 (Box 8, Folder 350-51)
    - Vernadsky, George, 1964-68 (Box 8, Folder 352)
    - Vinslov, IA.
      See: Russkoe ob"edinennoe obshchestvo..., Box 6, folder 293
    - Vishniak, Mark, 1938, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 353)
    - Vodov, Sergei
    - Voloshin, Aleksandr, 1941-60 (Box 8, Folder 354-57)
    - Vol'skaia, Valentina, 1964-70 (Box 8, Folder 358)
    - Vols'kii, Nikolai, 1956-64, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 359-61)
    - Vosniatskii, Anastasii, 1932-63 (Box 8, Folder 362-63)
    - "W" general, 1942-56 (Box 8, Folder 364)
    - Welfare Institution for Greek Orthodox
      See: Komitet po delam.. ., Box 4, folder 157
    - "Z" general, 1947-70 (Box 8, Folder 365)
    - Zagorodskii, Kornei, 1959-70 (Box 8, Folder 366)
    - Zaitsev, Boris, 1947-71 (Box 8, Folder 367-71)
    - Zak, A., 1949, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 372)
    - Zeccola, Richard, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 373)
    - Zenzinov, Vladimir, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 374)
    - Zhenuk, Sergei, 1942-72 (Box 8, Folder 375-78)
    - Zlobin, Vladimir, 1953, 1961, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 379)
    - Zurov, Leonid, 1953-71 (Box 8, Folder 380)
    - Anonymous, 1955-68, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 381)
    - Unidentified, 1937-72, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 382-84)
  - OUTGOING
    - "A" general, 1948-49 (Box 9, Folder 385)
    - Aldanov, Mark, 1954, 56 (Box 9, Folder 386)
    - Avrorov, Konstantin, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 387)
    - "B" general, 1953-69 (Box 9, Folder 388)
    - Beklemishev, Anatolii, 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 389)
    - Berëzov, Rodion, 1953-55 (Box 9, Folder 390)
    - Bertenson, Sergei, 1951 Feb 15 (Box 9, Folder 391)
    - Bobrov, N., 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 392)
    - Boldyrev, K., 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 393)
    - Branlovskaia, Sof'ia, 1959 Mar 19 (Box 9, Folder 394)
    - Bunin, Ivan Bunina, Vera, 1951-55 (Box 9, Folder 395)
    - "C" general, 1952-71 (Box 9, Folder 396)
    - Chavchadze, Pavel, 1951, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 397)
    - Chebotarev, Grigorii, 1954 Mar 2 (Box 9, Folder 398)
    - Chekver, R., 1954 Jan 6 (Box 9, Folder 399)
    - Chepigo, Ekaterina, 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 400)
    - Chinnov, Igor, 1952-54 (Box 9, Folder 401)
    - Chukhnov, Nikolai, 1953 Oct 27 (Box 9, Folder 402)
    - Churaev, Anatolii, 1954 Aug 6 (Box 9, Folder 403)
    - Demidovich, N., 1948 Nov 11 (Box 9, Folder 404)
    - Denikina, Ksen'ia, 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 405)
    - Dimitrenko, V., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 406)
    - "F" general, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 407)
    - "G" general, 1952-71 (Box 9, Folder 408-09)
    - Gabrilovich, Leonid, 1948-52 (Box 9, Folder 410)
    - Gidaspova, Tat'iana, 1971 Apr 20 (Box 9, Folder 411)
    - Gins, Grigorii, 1969 Mar 21 (Box 9, Folder 412)
    - Glovatskaia, Ruth, 1969 Dec 2 (Box 9, Folder 413)
    - Gol'dshtein, Mikhail, 1969 Nov 13 (Box 9, Folder 414)
    - Golubintsev, Sviatoslav, 1969 Jun 14 (Box 9, Folder 415)
    - Graw, Regina, 1970-71 (Box 9, Folder 416)
    - Grebenshchikov, Grigorii, 1953 Mar 26 (Box 9, Folder 417)
    - Gul', Roman, 1969 Jul 24 (Box 9, Folder 418)
    - IAblonovskii, Sergei, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 419)
    - "K" general, 1952-71 (Box 9, Folder 420-21)
    - Karateev, Mikhail, 1970 Dec 28 (Box 9, Folder 422)
    - Karpik, Iulian, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 423)
    - Karsavin, Pavel, 1938 May 19 (Box 9, Folder 424)
    - Katenev, NIkolai, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 425)
    - Krotkov, IUrii, 1969-71 (Box 9, Folder 426)
    - Kruzenshtern-Peterets, IUstin'ia, 1970 Aug 27 (Box 9, Folder 427)
    - Krymova, Berta, 1969 May 15 (Box 9, Folder 428)
    - Kuskova, Ekaterina, 1957 Jun 18 (Box 9, Folder 429)
    - Kuznetsova, Galina, 1970 Jan 8 (Box 9, Folder 430)
    - "L" general, 1936-51 (Box 9, Folder 431)
    - Lebedev, Vladimir, 1937 Jun 26 (Box 9, Folder 432)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1972 Oct 16 (Box 9, Folder 433)
    - L'Oeuvre, 1939 Oct (Box 9, Folder 434)
    - Ostromyslenskii, Ivan, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 435)
    - "P" general, 1969-71 (Box 9, Folder 436-37)
    - Pachmuss, Temira, 1970 Apr 17 (Box 9, Folder 438)
    - Panteleimonov, Boris, 1949 Nov 17 (Box 9, Folder 439)
    - Pantiukhov, Oleg, 1969 Jan 27 (Box 9, Folder 440)
    - Perov, Pavel, 1969, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 441)
    - Petrov, Vladimir, 1948-49 (Box 9, Folder 442-44)
    - Pletnev, Rostislav, 1969-70 (Box 9, Folder 445)
    - Poliakov, Aleksandr, 1970-71 (Box 9, Folder 446)
    - Posev, 1970 Jul 29 (Box 9, Folder 447)
    - Pozdniakov, Vladimir, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 448)
    - Pushkarëv, Sergei, 1969-70 (Box 9, Folder 449)
    - "R" general, 1936-68 (Box 9, Folder 450)
    - Russkaia mysl', 1969 Jan 22 (Box 9, Folder 451)
    - "S" general, 1970-71 (Box 9, Folder 452)
    - Samarin, Vladimir, 1970 Feb 16 (Box 9, Folder 453)
    - Shvarts, Solomon, 1970 Feb 16 (Box 9, Folder 454)
    - Skrylov, Aleksandr, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 455)
    - Slonim, Mark, 1970-71 (Box 9, Folder 456)
    - Stepanov, N., 1969 May 7 (Box 9, Folder 457)
    - Stepanova, Natal'ia, 1970 Aug 4 (Box 9, Folder 458)
    - Struve, Gleb, 1948 Aug 3 (Box 9, Folder 459)
    - "T" general, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 460)
    - Teffi, Nadezhda, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 461)
    - Tolstoy Foundation, 1944 Mar 7 (Box 9, Folder 462)
    - "U" general, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 463)
    - Voloshin, Aleksandr, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 464)
    - Vol'skaia, Valentina, 1965, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 465)
    - Vol'skii, Nikolai, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 466)
    - Zaitsev, Boris, 1965 Jul 6 (Box 9, Folder 467)
    - Zhenuk, Sergei, 1970 Dec 15 (Box 9, Folder 468)
    - Unidentified, 1943 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 469)
  - THIRD PARTY
    - Aldanov, Mark to: (Box 10, Folder 470)
      - Nina Miliukova, 1947-51
      - Ludwig Grigor'evich..., 1954 Jul 27
    - Alekseev, A. G. to: (Box 10, Folder 471)
      - Aleksandra Tolstaia, 1947 Sep 18
    - Bernardo to: (Box 10, Folder 472)
      - Aleksei Leonidovich, 1926 Apr 16, n.d.
    - Bunina Vera to: (Box 10, Folder 473)
      - Ekaterina Kuskova, 1955 Jan 16
    - Burtsev, V. to: (Box 10, Folder 474)
      - Anatolii Brailovskii, 1935 May 24
    - Chukovskaia, Lidiia to: (Box 10, Folder 475)
      - Mikhail Sholokhov, n.d.
    - El'kin, Boris to: (Box 10, Folder 476)
      - Nina Miliukova, 1946 Oct 22, n.d.
    - Gershuni, IAkov to: (Box 10, Folder 477)
      - B. Avksent'eva, 1969 Nov 2
    - Il'in, Vladimir to: (Box 10, Folder 478)
      - Nikolai Ivanovich, 1969 [Aug 12]
    - Kantsyru, M. to: (Box 10, Folder 479)
      - B. Avksent'eva, 1967 Nov 9
    - Kheifets, IAkov to: (Box 10, Folder 480)
      - Aleksandr Konstantinovich
    - Kuznetsov, Anatolii to: (Box 10, Folder 481)
      - Nikolai Ul'ianov, n.d.
    - Mako, Sergei to: (Box 10, Folder 482)
      - B. Avksent'eva, 1953 Oct 30
    - Merezhkovskii, Dmitrii to: (Box 10, Folder 483)
      - N. Dolgopolov, 1941 Jun 19
    - Mikulovskii, Iosif to: (Box 10, Folder 484)
      - Ekaterina Kuskova, 1951 Mar 1
    - Miliukova, Nina to: (Box 10, Folder 485)
      - unidentified, n.d.
    - Prokopovich, Sergei to: (Box 10, Folder 486)
      - Nikolai Avksent'ev, 1941 Jun 12
    - Rashkov, A. to: (Box 10, Folder 487)
      - Ivanov, n.d.
    - Rohracher, Herbert to: (Box 10, Folder 488)
      - V. Glazkov, 1970 Jan 27
    - Tarnerov, N. to: (Box 10, Folder 489)
      - E. Chandler, 1956 Feb 25
    - Teffi to: (Box 10, Folder 490)
      - Mariia Tsetlin, 1948 May 20
- Writings, 1934-73; Series II; 1; (3 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is arranged alphabetically by author. Unsigned and unidentified pieces have been placed at the end of the series.
  - Adamovich, Georgii
    - Review of Mark Aldanov's Samoubiistvo: typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 491)
  - Aldanov, Mark
    - Pavlin'e pero: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 492-99)
  - Alekseeva, Lidiia
    - "Na smert' otsa narodov" (poem): holograph with cover letter, 1953 Mar 18 (Box 11, Folder 500)
  - Aronson, N.
    - Fragment: typescript, 1942 May 2 (Box 11, Folder 501)
  - Arsen'ev, Nikolai
    - "Aleksandr Chicherin (1793-1813)": printed version (Box 11, Folder 502)
    - "Moi vospominaniia o Moskovskom Universitete (1906-1910)": printed version, annotated, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 503)
    - "Poeziia grafa A.K. Tolstogo": printed version, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 504)
  - Barkhatov, Platon
    - Sovetskaia Katorga, Part I, "Vospominaniia politzakliuchennogo": typescript, bound, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 505)
    - Sovetskaia Katorga, Part II, "Belomorkanal": typescript, bound, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 506)
  - Belinkov, Arkadii
    - Praga, vesna, zima...": typescript copy, corrected, 1969 Jun 20 (Box 11, Folder 507)
  - Bunin, Ivan
    - "K moim vospominaniiam": typescript, corrected, 1953 May 6 (Box 11, Folder 508)
    - "Tretii Tolstoi": typescript, corrected, incomplete, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 509)
  - Dobuzhinskii, M.
    - Pamiati ushedshikh": holograph, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 510)
  - Domogatskii, Boris
    - "Ot pluga K pisatel'skomu peru": typescript, 1961 Nov 19 (Box 11, Folder 511)
  - Duvan, S. S.
    - "Imperator Nikolai II": typescript with holograph cover letter and photograph, 1953 Oct 14 (Box 11, Folder 512)
  - Ermakov, S.
    - "Na farme R.O.O.V.A.": holograph, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 513)
  - Fokin, Mikhail
    - Fragment: holograph, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 514)
  - Grechaninov, Aleksandr
    - "Russkoe tserkovnoe penie ot ego vozniknoveniia do nashikh dnei": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 515)
  - Ioann, Archbishop of San Fransisco
    - "Ot publikuiushehego dokumenty": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 517)
  - KHrabrov, Nikolai
    - "Kratkiia biograficheskiia svedeniia": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 518)
  - Kodrianskaia, Natalia
    - Skazki: typescripts with holograph lists, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 519-28)
  - Kolianskii, N.
    - Mir i dusha: typescript copy, bound, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 529)
  - Kornosevich, R. M.
    - Poems: typescripts, 1944-50 (Box 12, Folder 530)
  - Korovin, Konstantin
    - Memuary-Moia zhizn': typescripts, 1934-35 (Box 12, Folder 531-41)
    - "Urok zhivopisi": typescript, corrected, 1934 Mar 13 (Box 12, Folder 542)
  - Krasnov, A.
    - "O dvukh shutovskikh stateikakh i ob odnoi ochen' ser'eznoi veshchi": typescript, copy, [1959-60] (Box 12, Folder 543)
    - "Kuda ty idesh, Volodia?": typescript, copy, [1960] (Box 12, Folder 544)
    - "Protiv dezinformatsii i klevety": typescript, copy, [1960] (Box 12, Folder 545)
    - "Perepiska s drugom-kommunistom": typescript, copy, 1961 Jan 11 (Box 12, Folder 546)
  - Krotkov, IUrii
    - "KGB i intelligentsiia": typescript, corrected, with holograph sheet of corrections, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 547)
  - Kuskova, Ekaterina
    - "Narodnyi Traur": holograph fragment, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 548)
  - Kuznetzov, S.
    - "TSvetushchii Krai": typescript, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 549)
  - Mozhaiskaia, O.
    - "Vinston Cherchil'- Nobelevskii laureat po literature": typescript, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 550)
  - Nekrasov, Vladimir
    - "Zagadka G. P. Fedotova": typescript, 1943 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 551)
  - Nikodimov, I.
    - O politieheskom obrazovanii v SSSR: printed version, Munich, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 552)
  - Osipov, N.
    - "Polia nevedomoi zemli. G. B. Mesniaev", 1962 (Box 12, Folder 553)
  - Pal'chikov, S.
    - "Babka", (poem): typescript, 1949 Feb 28 (Box 12, Folder 554)
  - Peregonov, Ivan
    - "Krasnoarmeets v adu": holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 555)
  - Petrishchev, A.
    - "Kak otbivalis' ot Kommun": holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 556)
    - "Novye mysli o trekh diktatorakh": holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 557)
    - "Prorochestvo ob Amerike i Rossii": holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 558)
    - "Russkoe zoloto": holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 559)
  - Pomerantsev, Kiril
    - "Kogda spor nevozmozhen": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 560)
  - Radio Liberation
    - "Kreml' i frantsuzkie sotsialisty": typescript, 1957 Jun (Box 12, Folder 561)
  - Rafal'skii, Sergei
    - "Nasha malen'kaia zhizn'": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 562)
    - "Ne streliaite v pianista, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 563)
  - Remizov, Aleksei
    - Poem: holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 564)
  - Rubisova, E.
    - Article about Mark Weinbaum: printed version, 1973 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 565)
  - Savin, Dormidont
    - Rozhdenie novoi ery: typescripts, corrected, 1963 Dec 10 (Box 12, Folder 566)
  - Shiriaev, Boris
    - "Tretii Tolstoi": holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 567)
  - Shostak, Vladimir
    - "Samovnushenie zhelaemogo vmesto deistvitel'nosti": typescript with cover letter, enclosure, 1964 Mar 6 (Box 12, Folder 568)
  - Sibirskii, Konstantin
    - Chernaia ten' nad moim solnechnym zavtra: printed, with letter on inside cover., 1948
      See: Restricted Fragile Papers, Box 16, folder 630
  - Toroshin, A.
    - "Panaiota": holograph, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 569)
  - Trubetskoi, IUrii
    - "Portrety sovremennikov. III. M. A. (Box 13, Folder 570)
      - Aldanov": holograph, n.d.
  - Turtsevich, M. L.
    - Dni nashei zhizni: typescript, bound, 1939-45 (Box 13, Folder 571)
  - Valentinov, Nikolai
    - "Chrevoveshchatel' nevniatits": typescript, incomplete, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 572)
  - Veidle, Vladimir
    - "Venetsiia 1968": typescript, incomplete (Box 13, Folder 573-76)
    - "1896-1966": typescript, copy, 1966 Jun (Box 13, Folder 577)
  - Voloshin, Aleksandr
    - Na putiakh i pereput'iakh: printed, San Fransisco, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 578)
  - Weinbaum, Mark
    - "Dolg sovesti- dolg chesti": reprinted excerpt from Novoe russkoe slovo, 1950 Nov 15, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 579)
    - "Pavel Aleksandrovich Chavchadze": printed version, 1971 Jul 14 (Box 13, Folder 580)
  - Zagor, T.
    - "Kievskie Kontrakty", 1966 Feb 18 (Box 13, Folder 581)
  - Zhakmon, Pavel
    - Poems: typescript, 1968 Nov 8 (Box 13, Folder 582)
  - Unsigned
    - "Delo A. Evalenko v Niu Iorke" unsigned, possibly incomplete; typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 583)
    - "General I. V. Turchaninov" "Na mogile generala I. V. Turehaninova": signed "O. G."; typescript, copy, [1962] (Box 13, Folder 584)
    - Unidentified, 1943, 1967, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 585-86)
- Other Papers, 1896-1968; Series III; 0.25; (1 box) + 1 art storage item
  - Bakunina, Ekaterina: photograph, inscribed, 1959 Jun 19 (Box 14, Folder 587)
  - Grigor'ev, Boris: exhibition catalog, possibly incomplete, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 588)
  - Photograph of a painting, [post 1937]
  - Newspaper clippings, 1938, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 589)
  - Ishevskii, Dimitrii: identity card, 1936 Dec 28 (Box 14, Folder 590)
  - Klimov, Eugenii: Ce qui s'en va Quebec: printed albums of lithographs, 1953 Dec (Box 14, Folder 591-92)
  - Novoe russkoe slovo
    - Newspaper clippings, 1947-49 (Box 14, Folder 593)
    - Radio piece for Russian Branch IBS about the newspaper: typescript, copy, 1960 Mar 19 (Box 14, Folder 594)
  - Remizov, Aleksei: title lists, holographs, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 595)
  - Russian émigrés: biographical sketches (some English), including Bunin, Zen'kovskii, others, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 596)
  - Chaliapin, Fyodor: sketch, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 597)